Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII. CEIP Library
  - Subseries VIII.A: CEIP reports and publications
    - Division of International Law
      - Zeydel, Walter H. Annotation of the charter of the United Nations and statute of the international court of justice. 1947 (Box 341)
    - Eliot, Charles William. Recommendations… for the expenditure of money in China and Japan by the Carnegie endowment… or by other American endowments. 1913 (Box 341)
    - International economic conference, London, March, 1935. 1935 (Box 341)
    - International Relations Clubs News Bulletin. 1947 1948 (Box 341)
    - International visits of representative men. United States-Latin America. Instructions to Robert Bacon. 1913 (Box 341)
    - Lecture tour of Mr. Clarence A Phillips to Europe in the summer of 1931. Report. 1931 (Box 341)
    - Lists of libraries and Institutions in which the publications of the Carnegie Endowment are depositeed for free use. 1922 1926 1928 (Box 341)
    - Lists of publications of the Carnegie Endowment. 1916-1928 (Box 341)
    - Memorandum for the Information of the Board of Trustees in the semi-annual meeting Decmeber 16, 1918. (Box 341)
    - Office of the secretary
      - Plan of annuities and insurance. 1922 (Box 341)
      - Plan to enable personnel of the Endowment to participate in the Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America. 1919 (Box 341)
      - Publications of the Endowment. Rules for marking printer's copy. 1914 (Box 341)
    - Officers for the year 1916-1917 (Box 341)
    - Programs of dinners, etc. (Box 341)
    - Requirements for appropriation. 1917 1918 1920 (Box 341)
    - Resolutions (Box 341)
    - Root, Elihu and Nicholas Murray Butler. Problems confronting the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. 1920 (Box 342)
    - Scott, James Brown. The development of modern diplomacy. 1921 (Box 342)
    - Special committee on policy appointed February16, 1925. Report as amended December 2, 1926. 1927 (Box 342)
    - Trustees. Statement. 1915 Feb (Box 342)
    - Visit of American editorial writers to The Hague. August 7-12, 1927. Final programme. 1927 (Box 342)
    - Visit of American professors of international relations to The Hague. August 10-13, 1926. 1926 (Box 342)
  - Subseries VIII.B: Other publications
    - American Bar Association. 1. Section of International and Comparative Law. Neutrality and International Sanctions. 1936. 2. Committee for Peace and Law through United Nations. The progressive development of international law. 1947 (Box 342)
    - American Friends Service Committee. 1944 Volunteer Service Projects. 1944 (Box 342)
    - American Society of International Law. Program of twelfth annual meeting. 1921 (Box 342)
    - The American Student Endowment for Forcible International Peace (Box 342)
    - American Youth Hostel. Knapsack. 1946 (Box 342)
    - Anti-complulsory Military Drill League. Open letter. 1925 (Box 342)
    - Andrew Carnegie 1935-1919 (Box 342)
    - The Arbitrator. Journal of the International Arbitration League. March1949 (Box 342)
    - Association for International conciliation, American branch. Constitution and by-laws… undated & List of publications…no. 1. 1919 (Box 342)
    - Ayala, Eusebio. Pacto antibelico (aprobado en sesion del 7 de agosto de 1929)… 1929 (Box 342)
    - Barthel, Ernst. Deutchland-Frankreich. 1935 (Box 342)
    - Bauerle, Albert T. Peace by Force or Chaos. 1936 (Box 342)
    - Bonney, Thérèse. Europe's Children. Pictorial report. 1943 (Box 342)
    - Boorse, Henry A. Report on international scientific conferences held in England, July, 1946. 1946 (Box 342)
    - Bosch, Juan. Mujeres en la vida de hostos. 1939 (Box 342)
    - Bray, Dr. John F.L. A Plea for Gold. 1942 (Box 342)
    - Brinkman, Ray. Adequate Income for Endowment Fund Investments. 1940 (Box 342)
    - Bulow, Einar ValdeMarchAmerica Think! 1941 (Box 342)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murrary. The world today. (Box 342)
    - Caminiti. Reward: The Adventure of Veronka the Little Immigrant. 1936 (Box 342)
    - Carnegie, Andrew
      - Armaments and their results. 1909 (Box 343)
      - Arbitration. 1911 (Box 343)
      - The palace of peace. 1913 (Box 343)
      - Speech at the annual meeting of the Peace Society. 1910 (Box 343)
    - Carnegie, Colonel David. The I.L.O. in world affairs. (Box 343)
    - Carnegie Hero Fund Commission. Report of the 32nd annual meeting. 1936 Jan (Box 343)
    - China Institute. Report of the director. 1945 May (Box 343)
    - Chirinos, Carlos Medinas. Nuevo Punto De Vista Para La Paz Universal. 1925 (Box 343)
    - The Church Peace Union
      - Record of twenty years: 1914-1934. 1935 (Box 343)
      - Report of the general secretary and auditors for the year 1936. 1937 (Box 343)
    - La Cité Universitaire de Paris. 1925 (Box 343)
    - The Cobden Club. Report for the year 1938. 1939 (Box 343)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System. CBS News on D-Day. 1945 (Box 343)
    - Commission to study the organization of peace. Statements, reports, clippings. 1946-1947 (Box 343)
    - The Consensus. April 1929 (Box 343)
    - Coulon, Madeleine. De graves événements dans le Barreau Roumain. (Les agissements racistes en Roumaine No.1). 1937 (Box 343)
    - Council for Inter-American Cooperation, Inc. Inter-American services: a selected guide to available aids. 1946 (Box 343)
    - Cromie, Leonard J. Provisional Report on the Study of Demographic Problems. 1937 (Box 343)
    - Crozier, Alfred Owen. Nation of Nations. 1915 (Box 343)
    - d'Estournelles devait savoir... 1915 (Box 343)
    - Dallex, V.Esquisse D'un Plan Pour Sortir De La Crise. 1935 (Box 343)
    - The Dawes Way: an international magazine. 1925 (Box 343)
    - The Declaration of the Federation of the World; a resolution. 1942 (Box 343)
    - Defaulted Debts of the Southern States of the USA. 1927 (Box 343)
    - Dennis, Alfred L.P. Stoking the fires of peace: the Carnegie Endowment has been busy since Christmas, 1910. 1921 (Box 343)
    - Dickinson, Edwin. What is wrong with International LawÀ 1946 (Box 343)
    - Diourdievitch, Tched.. Vers L'Union Monétaire Balkanique (Towards A Balkan Monetary Union). 1936 (Box 343)
    - Dominican Republic. Department of State for Foreign Relations. The candidacy of Rafeal L. Trujillo Molina and Stenio Vincent for the Nobel Peace Prize to be awarded in 1936. 1935 (Box 344)
    - Drucker, J.C.J. Some correspondence concerning a British Passport. 1918 (Box 344)
    - Dulles, John Foster. Statements and Addresses. 1945-1947 (Box 344)
    - Duncan, Ronald. The Complete Pacifist. (Box 344)
    - Dutch Anti-War Council (Nederlandische anti-oorlog raad). Brochure. 1914 (Box 344)
    - Editorial Research Reports. The Briand proposal and arbitration. 1927 (Box 344)
    - Emery, Brooks. Mainsprings of world politics: America's power position. 1943 (Box 344)
    - L'Europe Nouvelle. 1926 Jan (Box 344)
    - Filderman, W. Le problème de travail national et la crise du Barreau en Roumanie. 1937 (Box 344)
    - Fonck, René. Mes combats. 1920 (Box 344)
    - Founding of the National Roosevelt Library. 1947 (Box 344)
    - Figueira de Almeida, Theodoro. Diagram of a systematic plan for the solution of the war problems and for the assurance of the word's peace. 1924 (Box 344)
    - France. Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Diplomatic correspondence relating to reparations. 1923 (Box 344)
    - Genio latino. September -October 1941 (Box 344)
    - Good Reading: 1000 Books Briefly Described. 1938 (Box 344)
    - Gould, Frederick J. Educational prophets in Berlin. 1925 (Box 344)
    - Gourevitch, Boris.
      - The legal position of the refugees and stateless persons to whom the right of residence is refused in the West European Countries of refuge. 1939 (Box 344)
      - What can the United States do to defend human rights as the basic premise of social and international peaceÀ 1940 (Box 344)
    - Groupe Interparlementaire Suédois. Recueil De Documents. 1914 (Box 344)
    - Heller, Dr. Victor. Government price fixing and rationing in Austria during the War of 1914-1918. 1941 (Box 345)
    - Holland News. 1915-1919 (Box 345)
    - Heerfordt, C.F. An appeal to the European national in the U.S.A. 1935 & Esquisse d'un projet franco-scandinve concernant les "Articles Fondamentaux" de la constitution des "Etats-unis des Nations Européenes." 1929 (Box 345)
    - Inman, Samuel Guy. Caribbean Impressions. 1932 (Box 345)
    - Industrial Reorganization League. A policy of reconstruction to be implemented under the powers of an Industrail Reorganization (Enabling) Act. (Box 345)
    - The International Arbitration League. Report for 1948. (Box 345)
    - International Auxiliary Language Association (IALA). Variantes de le lingua internationale. 1947 (Box 345)
    - International Bureau of Education. Bulletin. 1932 April (Box 345)
    - International Chamber of Commerce Resolutions Posed at the Stockholm Congress Final report of the Trade Barriers Committee
      - Conte, Roger. Report on international industrial ententes. 1927 (Box 345)
      - Final Report of the Trade Barriers Committee. 1927 April (Box 345)
      - Resolutions passed atthe Stockholm Congress. 1927 (Box 345)
    - International Migration Service. Social Problems of Migrating Children. 1925 (Box 345)
    - Interparliamentary Union. American Group. 15th Annual meeting. 1918 (Box 345)
    - Jäckh, Ernst. America und Wir. 1929 (Box 345)
    - Journal of Bulgarian Chamber of Architects (with "Building principles of American and English libraries" by M. Demchevsky). 1938 (Box 345)
    - Journal of Educational Sociology. 1946 Dec (Box 345)
    - Handbook of International Relations (Box 345)
    - The League of Nations (serial). 1919 May 3, 1920 Feb 10 (Box 345)
    - Liang, Yuen-Li. The Pact of Paris as envisaged by Mr. Stimson: its significance in international law. 1932 (Box 346)
    - A List of 774 books published for American Armed Forces Overseas (Box 346)
    - Lorenz, Gabriel. Plan for International Organization for World Democracy. (Box 346)
    - Luckau, Alma. The German Delegation at the Paris Peace Conference. 1941 (Box 346)
    - Lüdke, Hermann. Abraham Lincoln. 1928 (Box 346)
    - Macedonian Political Organizatons, Central Committee of the Union of the. Resolutions. 1925 (Box 346)
    - Maddox, D.C.. For God and Peace. 1937 (Box 346)
    - Marcovici-Cléja, Simon. A way out of the Palestine difficulty and a solution to the world Jewish problems. 1938 (Box 346)
    - Martin, Charles E. Professors go to school: a clinical study of international relations. 1927 (Box 346)
    - Mead, Edwin D. Peace trustees and the armament craze. In Unity (Magazine), Volume LSS, October 3, 1912 (Box 346)
    - Memoire présenté au nom de la population bulgare de la macédoine sous domination yougoslave. 1930 (Box 346)
    - Memorial dirijido al comité nobel de Parlamento Noruego en que se propone al Generalisimo Doctor Rafael Leonidas Trujillo Molina como candidato al Premio Nobel de la Paz. 1936 (Box 346)
    - Morgan, J.H. Dominion Status. 1929 (Box 346)
    - The Nation Associates. A request for the suspension of Argentina from the United Nations. 1946 (Box 346)
    - National Centre Group. The National Centre Policy of Action. 1932 (Box 346)
    - National League of Women Voters. Various publications. 1924-1925 (Box 346)
    - National student forum on the Paris pact. Various publicatons. 1931-1938 (Box 347)
    - Nederhold, W.L. Scapegoat. 1935 (Box 347)
    - New Commonwealth Quarterly. 1935 April -June (Box 347)
    - New York State Department of Commerce. A Guide to State Services. 1946 (Box 347)
    - De Nordiske Interparlamentariske Grupper. Aarbog. 1919 (Box 347)
    - Nostrand, Howard Lee and Francis J. Brown. The role of colleges and universities in international understanding. 1949 (Box 347)
    - Nothomb, Pierre. Le people Belge et la guerre. 1914 (Box 347)
    - Organization Centrale Pour Une Paix Durable (The Central Organization for a Durable Peace). Various publications. 1916-1917 (Box 347)
    - Overseas News Agency. Newsletters. 1947 (Box 348)
    - Le Pacte de Paris. Pacte Briand-Kellogg. 1933 (Box 348)
    - The Palace of Peace (Album). (English and Dutch versions.) (Box 348)
    - Pan American Institute of Havana (Instituto Panamericano del la Habana). 1937 (Box 348)
    - Peace Conferences after the WarÀ A series of questions and answers by th Nederlandsche Anti-oorlog Raad. 1916 (Box 348)
    - Pezet, Frederico Alfonso. Contrast in the development of nationality in Anglo America and Latin America. 1916 (Box 348)
    - Popescu, Aureliu Ion. Fundatiile Rockefeller si Carnegie din Statele-Unite ale Americii… 1927 (Box 348)
    - Postwar Problems of the Pacific and World Organization. 1944 (Box 348)
    - Protocol for the pacific settlement of international disputes. 1925 (Box 348)
    - Reinsch, Paul. The Carnegie peace foundation. 1911 (Box 348)
    - Renunciation of war treaty, Paris August 27, 1928. The general pact for the renunciation of war. French and English texts of the pact as signed. 1928 (Box 348)
    - Research International. Quarterly appraisal of economic and political conditions in France. 1937 April -May (Box 348)
    - Robinson, Leland Rex. International labor legislation and international trade. 1937 (Box 348)
    - Root, Elihu. Address at the joint meeting of the subsection on international law and the American Institute of International Law. 1915 (Box 348)
    - The Royal Institute of International Affairs. Various publications. 1936-1938 1945 (Box 348)
    - Rueff, Jacques. La crise du capitalisme. 1925 (Box 348)
    - Ruhl, Arthur Brown. Seven million dollars worth of peace: how the Carnegie Endowment has been spend. In Survey geographic. 1924 (Box 348)
    - Russel, Nicholas. The Fog Signal. 1924 (Box 348)
    - Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee. The educational work of the Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee abroad & Financial report. 1929 (Box 348)
    - Sadler, G.T. The might of magnanimity. (Box 348)
    - Salter, Arthur. How to secure practical results. 1927 (Box 348)
    - Samson, Elizabeth. World peace program. 1933 (Box 348)
    - Sarkar, B.K. Die 1. Entwicklung und welthwirtschaftliche Bedeutung des modernen Indien. 1931. 2. Economic planning for Bengal. 1933. 3. Accident insurance in comparative legislation and statistics. 1933 (Box 348)
    - Saunier, Baudry de. Comment Paris a été détruit en six heures. 1921 (Box 348)
    - Save Carl V. Ossietzky! 1935 (Box 349)
    - Scholastic. 1925 Nov 14 (Box 349)
    - Schools for Overseas Administration (Box 349)
    - Scott, James Brown. Judicial settlement of international disuputes. 1912 Nov (Box 349)
    - Service Bureau for Women's Organizations. Annual report 1946-1947 (Box 349)
    - Shotwell, James T.
      - With Charles Hackett. Addresses delivered at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. 1933 (Box 349)
      - The Challenge to Peace (article in Our World, December 1924). 1924 (Box 349)
      - The Life of Woodrow Wilson: an outline for a course of study. (Box 349)
      - Sun Yat-Sen and Maurice William. 1932 (Box 349)
      - Survey of the Study of International Relations and Foreign Affairs in the United States. 1933 (Box 349)
    - Social Science Research Council. Report of the director of the program of research in international relations for 1931. 1932 (Box 349)
    - Société Anonyme des Hydroglisseurs de Lambert. Press kit (Box 349)
    - Sol, January A Scheme for World Peace. 1924 (Box 349)
    - Soto, J. de. Conceptions francaises de la sécurité dans le pacifique. 1947 (Box 349)
    - Stensgard, Erling. America laeger krigens saar. (Work of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.) 1923 (Box 349)
    - Supplemental list: Suits between States decided by the Supreme Court of the United States since June 10, 1918. 1939 (Box 349)
    - Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary force. (G-5 Division). Military Government Germany: Technical manual for education and religious affairs. 1945 (Box 349)
    - The Tenth Fortune Round Table on Demobilizing the War Economy. 1941 (Box 349)
    - The Textile Industry in the USA. 1937 (Box 349)
    - Tseng-Tsiang, Dom Pierre-Celestin Lou, O.S.B. 1.Les solennites de l'ordination sacerdotale du R.P. Dom... 1935. 2. L'invasion et l'occupation de la Mandchourie del la Doctrine Catholique par les écrits du Cardinal Mercier... 1937 (Box 350)
    - La Turquie Kamaliste. 1937 (Box 350)
    - Union Interparlementaire (Interperliamentary Union). Various publications. 1915-1920 (Box 350)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics. Constitution (Box 350)
    - United Nations. Various publications. 1944-1946 (Box 350)
    - United States. Chamber of Commerce. Releases. 1944 (Box 350)
    - United States. Congress. House. Committee on the judiciary. …Carnegie endowment for international peace… Report. (To accompany H.R. 1314). 1912 (Box 350)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on foreign relation. General pact for the renunciation of war. Hearings…70th Congress, 2nd session, on the general pact signed at Paris August 27, 1928. 1928 (Box 350)
    - United States. State Department. Office of Educational Exchanges. Various. 1946 (Box 350)
    - United States. War Department. Public Relations Divisions. Press releases. 1947 (Box 350)
    - The Universal Christian Conference on Life and Work (Box 350)
    - The University of Chicago Round Table. Gandhi's Life and Death: Its Meaning for Mankind. Radio discussion. 1948 (Box 350)
    - The Unofficial Ambassadors. 1932 (Box 350)
    - Uschkureit, G.A. The age of the holy spirit. 1929 (Box 350)
    - Volkerbund und Volkerrecht. 1936 Dec (Box 350)
    - Watters, Hilda M. International Relations for Secondary Schools. 1944 (Box 350)
    - Wavrinsky, Edvard. Den Svenska Riksdagens Interparlamentariska Grupp 1892-1917. 1917 (Box 350)
    - Whaley-Eaton Service. American letter. 1947 (Box 351)
    - Wilson, Nathaniel. In the matter of the appeal of the Carnegie endowment for international peace for the action of the Board of Personal tax appraisers… (Statement and Brief for Appellant). 1918 (Box 351)
    - Wolff, Marguerite. The Institute for Foreign Public Law and International Law in Berling. 1927 (Box 351)
    - World Alliance for Combating Anti Semitism. J'accuse! 1933 (Box 351)
    - World Associationn of Girl Guides and Girl Scouts. Seventh biennial report. 1942 (Box 351)
    - World Economic Conference. Reports. 1927 (Box 351)
    - World Federal Union. Various. 1938-1939 (Box 351)
    - The World Trade Foundation of America. 1. Community Project (Prepared for presentation to: Carnegie Corporation). 1946. 2. On utilizing the agricultural series by Blackwell Smith. 1946 (Box 351)
    - World Understanding Foundation. Chinese Unit. Architectural plans. (Box 351)
    - World's Permanent Industrial Exposition, Inc. Proposals (Box 351)
    - Wright, Joseph F. America and the Brotherhood of Nations. 1925 (Box 351)
    - Yale Institute of International Studies. Report 1945-1946. 1947 (Box 351)
    - Zeitschrift fur Politik. 1934 (Box 351)
  - Subseries VIII.C: Clippings re the Endowment
    - Other publications and articles on the endowment can be found throughout this series. (Box 351)
- Series IX. Oversize Material, (8 folders)
  - Division of Intercourse and Education-European Centre-Officers-Babcock, Earle-Posters for courses offered by the Endowment
    - 1925 (2) (Removed from box 107.1) (Box 352)
    - 1929 (Removed from box 109.4) (Box 352)
  - Projects
    - Committee to Aid Czechoslovakia-Hand drawn color map of the region (Removed from box 288.4) (Mapcase 14.05.09)
    - Committee on International Economic Policy-Trade charts (Removed from box 298.2) (Box 352)
    - Libraries-Reims-Plan de la nouvelle bibliotheque (2), 1923 (Removed from box 320.16) (Box 362)
    - Orient-Railway map of Manchuria and Mongolia, 1930 (Removed from box 323.9) (Mapcase 14.05.10)
    - Visiting Carnegie Professors-Dengler, Paul-Poster for music courses offered by the Austro-American Institute of Education, 1933 (Removed from box 330.5) (Box 352)
  - Miscellaneous
    - World Capital. Foundation of Internationalism. (map) (Mapcase 15.05.11)